<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<process version="3.4.1">

  <operator name="Root" class="Process">
      <description text="#ylt#table#ygt#  #ylt#tr#ygt#  #ylt#td#ygt# #ylt#icon#ygt#groups/24/io#ylt#/icon#ygt# #ylt#/td#ygt#  #ylt#td#ygt##ylt#p#ygt#Before we can examine the data and try to find a hypothesis which explain the inherent structure, the data is loaded from file. Therefore the first child operator named #yquot#Input#yquot# is used.#ylt#/p#ygt# #ylt#/td#ygt#  #ylt#/tr#ygt# #ylt#/table#ygt#   #ylt#p#ygt# If you select the input operator the property table on the right side shows some parameters of this operator. One of these parameters was printed with a different font. This means that this parameter is mandatory and must be defined for using this operator. An experiment can only be started if all mandatory parameters were defined.#ylt#/p#ygt#   #ylt#p#ygt# Try the following:#ylt#/p#ygt# #ylt#ul#ygt# #ylt#li#ygt#Press the #yquot#Play#yquot# button to start the experiment. After a few moments the experiment should end and the user interface automatically changes to the #yquot#Results#yquot# mode. The loaded data (example set) is shown together with some basic statistics.#ylt#/li#ygt# #ylt#li#ygt#Go back into edit view and change between the tabs #yquot#Parameters#yquot#, #yquot#XML#yquot#, #yquot#Comment#yquot#, and #yquot#New Operator#yquot#. The first three tabs can be used to make changes of the current experiment or the currently selected operator. Parameters allow the adaption of parameters of the currently selected operator. The XML view can be used to quickly change the experiment setup. The Comment tab can be used to define user descriptions or comments for the current operator. The New Operator tab provides all operators of the RapidMiner operator repository in a grouped view allowing for dragging new operators into the operator tree.#ylt#/li#ygt# #ylt#li#ygt#Select the input operator. The file determined by the #yquot#attributes#yquot# parameter is an attribute description file which describes the data. Click on the edit button to start the attribute editor. With the attribute editor you can easily load your data and create the attribute description files used by RapidMiner.#ylt#/li#ygt##ylt#/ul#ygt# #ylt#p#ygt#The easiest way to configure this very important operator is to use the configuration wizard which will be started by pressing the button at the top of the parameter table!#ylt#/p#ygt#"/>
      <operator name="Input" class="ExampleSource">
          <parameter key="attributes"	value="../data/golf.aml"/>
      </operator>
  </operator>

</process>
