<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<process version="4.0beta">
<operator name="Root" class="Process">
  <description text="#ylt#p#ygt# The ARFF file format of Weka is also often used to describe the data. This experiment uses an ArffExampleSource operator to read data and attribute descriptions from files in ARFF format. #ylt#/p#ygt#  #ylt#p#ygt# Several ways exist to load your data into RapidMiner, for example: #ylt#/p#ygt#

#ylt#ul#ygt#
#ylt#li#ygt#The #ylt#b#ygt#ExampleSource#ylt#/b#ygt# operator can be used for most dense data formats. It allows an arbitrary definition of separating characters. The default values should be sufficient for most applications and data sets. This operator is also used to create attribute description files just from your data (Edit button). This operator also provides a configuration wizard for loading data sets.#ylt#br#ygt##ylt#icon#ygt#24/data#ylt#/icon#ygt##ylt#/li#ygt#
#ylt#li#ygt#The #ylt#b#ygt#ExcelExampleSource#ylt#/b#ygt# operator can be used to load data directly from Excel spread sheets.#ylt#/li#ygt#
#ylt#li#ygt#The #ylt#b#ygt#SparseFormatExampleSource#ylt#/b#ygt# can read most sparse data formats known from SVMs. Like for the normal ExampleSource operator, parameters define the data details.#ylt#/li#ygt#
#ylt#li#ygt#The #ylt#b#ygt#ArffExampleSource#ylt#/b#ygt# operator can be used for the data formats ARFF which is used by Weka.#ylt#/li#ygt#
#ylt#li#ygt#Other #ylt#b#ygt#XXXExampleSource#ylt#/b#ygt# operators exist to load data which is given in other special file formats like CSV, C4.5, BibTeX, or dBase.#ylt#/li#ygt# #ylt#li#ygt#The #ylt#b#ygt#DatabaseExampleSource#ylt#/b#ygt# can read your data directly from a database table. Please refer to the sample experiments and the operator description in the RapidMiner tutorial. #ylt#br#ygt##ylt#icon#ygt#24/data_connection#ylt#/icon#ygt##ylt#/li#ygt#
#ylt#li#ygt#The #ylt#b#ygt#ExampleSetGenerator#ylt#/b#ygt# creates random example sets for testing purposes based on a user defined target function.#ylt#/li#ygt#
#ylt#/ul#ygt#"/>
  <operator name="Input" class="ArffExampleSource">
    <parameter key="data_file"	value="../data/iris.arff"/>
    <parameter key="label_attribute"	value="class"/>
  </operator>
</operator>
</process>

