<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<process version="4.0beta2">

  <operator name="Root" class="Process">
      <description text="#ylt#p#ygt#Sometimes the selection of features alone is insufficient. In these cases other transformations of the feature space must be performed. The generation of new attributes from the given attributes extends the feature space. Maybe a hypothesis can be easily found in the extended feature space. #ylt#/p#ygt##ylt#p#ygt#YAGGA (Yet Another Generating Genetic Algorithm) is a hybrid feature selection / generation wrapper. The performance estimation is done with an inner cross validation building block. Of course other ways of performance estimation are also possible. The probability for feature generation depends on the probability for feature removal. This ensures that the average length of feature sets remains until shorter or longer feature sets prove to be better. #ylt#/p#ygt##ylt#p#ygt#When YAGGA finished the transformation, new features were constructed. In many cases this optimal feature set should be used on other data, too. Therefore the optimal attribute set is written into a file. In the next example we will see how these files can be used to transform new data into the optimal learning representation. #ylt#/p#ygt##ylt#p#ygt#Try the following:  #ylt#ul#ygt##ylt#li#ygt#Start the experiment. The transformed input example set, the performance estimation, and a weights vector is delivered as result. All feature operators like YAGGA have a parameter #yquot#apply_best_weights#yquot# (only in expert mode). How the result changes when using this parameter?#ylt#/li#ygt##ylt#li#ygt#Try to add an experiment log operator. Since YAGGA does only allow one inner operator, you have to add a simple operator chain (from the #yquot#core#yquot# group) to YAGGA. Right click on the cross validation operator and use cut and paste the cross validation into the added chain. Add an experiment log operator into the chain. Add the values you would like to plot to the parameter list of the experiment log operator. Please refer to the RapidMiner Tutorial for further explanations. #ylt#table#ygt##ylt#tr#ygt##ylt#td#ygt##ylt#icon#ygt#operators/24/chain#ylt#/icon#ygt##ylt#/td#ygt##ylt#td#ygt##ylt#i#ygt#A simple operator chain to merge several operators.#ylt#/i#ygt##ylt#/td#ygt##ylt#/tr#ygt##ylt#tr#ygt##ylt#td#ygt##ylt#icon#ygt#24/cut#ylt#/icon#ygt##ylt#/td#ygt##ylt#td#ygt##ylt#i#ygt#Cuts an operator from the operator tree.#ylt#/i#ygt##ylt#/td#ygt##ylt#/tr#ygt##ylt#tr#ygt##ylt#td#ygt##ylt#icon#ygt#24/paste#ylt#/icon#ygt##ylt#/td#ygt##ylt#td#ygt##ylt#i#ygt#Pastes a formerly cutted operator into the selected operator chain.#ylt#/i#ygt##ylt#/td#ygt##ylt#/tr#ygt##ylt#/table#ygt##ylt#/li#ygt##ylt#/ul#ygt##ylt#/p#ygt#"/>
      <parameter key="random_seed"	value="1997"/>
      <operator name="Input" class="ExampleSource">
          <parameter key="attributes"	value="../data/polynomial.aml"/>
      </operator>
      <operator name="YAGGA" class="YAGGA">
          <parameter key="maximum_number_of_generations"	value="50"/>
          <parameter key="population_size"	value="10"/>
          <parameter key="reciprocal_value"	value="false"/>
          <parameter key="tournament_size"	value="0.2"/>
          <parameter key="use_plus"	value="false"/>
          <operator name="SimpleValidation" class="SimpleValidation">
              <operator name="LinearRegression" class="LinearRegression">
              </operator>
              <operator name="ApplierChain" class="OperatorChain">
                  <operator name="Applier" class="ModelApplier">
                      <list key="application_parameters">
                      </list>
                  </operator>
                  <operator name="RegressionPerformance" class="RegressionPerformance">
                      <parameter key="root_relative_squared_error"	value="true"/>
                  </operator>
              </operator>
          </operator>
          <operator name="ProcessLog" class="ProcessLog">
              <list key="log">
                <parameter key="generation"	value="operator.YAGGA.value.generation"/>
                <parameter key="performance"	value="operator.YAGGA.value.performance"/>
                <parameter key="best"	value="operator.YAGGA.value.best"/>
              </list>
          </operator>
      </operator>
      <operator name="AttributeConstructionsWriter" class="AttributeConstructionsWriter">
          <parameter key="attribute_constructions_file"	value="yagga.att"/>
      </operator>
  </operator>

</process>
